<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Everyday News</string>
    <string name="news1_title">Two more blocks of hearings for inquiry into fatal helicopter crash</string>
    <string name="news1_desc">  At least two more rounds of hearings will be needed to get a full enough picture of how and why four army airmen died in a helicopter crash during a military exercise.

Captain Danniel Lyon, Lieutenant Maxwell Nugent, Warrant Officer Class Two Joseph Laycock and Corporal Alexander Naggs were killed when their Taipan MRH-90 ditched into the ocean south of Hamilton Island on July 28 last year.

The aircraft, with the call sign Bushman 83, was participating in Exercise Talisman Sabre and flying in formation with three other helicopters when the aircraft climbed suddenly before pitching nose first towards the water. about 10pm.
    </string>

    <string name="news2_title">Greens say Labor is failing Australians as new housing report paints grim picture</string>
    <string name="news2_desc"> Labor is “catastrophically failing” to meet the challenge of Australia’s worsening housing crisis, the Greens say, after a new government report revealed massive issues in the system.

    The National Housing Supply and Affordability Council has handed its inaugural State of the Housing System annual report to Housing Minister Julie Collins this week, finding housing affordability had significantly worsened in 2023 and supply was failing to keep up with demand.

    </string>
    Council chair Susan Lloyd-Hurwitz said social housing availability had not kept up with demand either, and could be further exacerbated by the pressures of rising rents in the private market.
    <string name="news3_title">Man arrested after allegedly brandishing knife in busy shopping centre</string>
    <string name="news3_desc">Shoppers were left in a panic on Friday after a man allegedly stole a knife from a grocery store and began brandishing it around a busy shopping centre on the outskirts of Melbourne.

        The man, 30, allegedly took the knife from a store at Watergardens Shopping Centre in Taylors Lakes and brandished it in the centre on Friday afternoon.

        Police allege he used the knife to assault and threaten a 21-year-old man and a 20-year-old woman inside the centre about 12.50pm.</string>
    <string name="news4_title">Hundreds protest Palestine-Israel conflict at peaceful rally</string>
    <string name="news4_desc">Hundreds of uni students have attended a rally protesting the Palestine-Israel conflict as students around the world stand in solidarity with the people of Gaza.

    The University of Sydney’s front lawns have been swallowed by tents this week as students continue their peaceful protest against the war.

        Similar protests are taking place at university campuses around the world, with one at New York’s Columbia University descending into chaos as police stormed a building, leading to about 300 arrests.</string>
    <string name="news5_title">‘Our sons and daughters’: Family unleash after 22-year-old surfer was stabbed to death</string>
    <string name="news5_desc">
    Ex-cop charged with perjury over de Belin trial
    Ex-cop charged with perjury over de Belin trial
    Desperate search for missing dad
    Desperate search for missing dad
    Shock after sudden death of popular mayor
    Shock after sudden death of popular mayor
    The uncle of a young man allegedly stabbed moments after leaving the surf at a NSW beach has expressed his heartbreak and anger over his nephew’s death, calling on the state government to take action on knife crime.

    The 22-year-old surfer, who is yet to be publicly identified, was found with significant stab wounds beside an orange sedan at Park Beach Reserve car park at Coffs Harbour shortly before 7am on Thursday.

    He was treated by paramedics before he was rushed to hospital – the same hospital where his mother works. But he was later confirmed dead.

    NSW Police Chief Inspector Detective Guy Flaherty told the ABC officers believed the 22-year-old had only recently exited the surf and was his wearing black swimsuit.

    Speaking with Ben Fordham on 2GB on Friday, the surfer’s uncle, identified only as Ralph, said he’s been left “broken” and “angry” over his nephew’s “senseless” death.

        “I’m angry obviously at this attacker. But I’m angry about politicians (too),” he said.</string>
    <string name="news6_title">Bob Carr threatens legal action against NZ deputy PM Winston Peters</string>
    <string name="news6_desc">Bob Carr and New Zealand’s Deputy Prime Minister have ratcheted up their clash over AUKUS, as the former premier and foreign minister threatens legal action over a comment.

    Amid discussions New Zealand may play a part in AUKUS Pillar 2 – which Mr Carr strongly opposes – Winston Peters made comments about Mr Carr and China on Radio NZ on Thursday.

    It spurred Mr Carr to threaten legal action against Mr Peters, who is also New Zealand’s Foreign Minister.

    The spat continued on Friday morning, when Mr Peters took to X to seemingly fire another shot at Mr Carr.

    “We should never be accepting of any irrelevant ill-informed shill from some other country to walk into New Zealand and try to tell us what to do,” Mr Peters wrote.

    “Here in New Zealand we respect something called a ‘country’s independent nationhood’. That principle seems lost on these people who just use it as a punchline.”

    A few hours later, he shared quotes from an RNZ interview where he said he was “in for a legal fight” with Mr Carr.

        “I’m not a coward, I’m standing up for the rights and principles of our society,” he told RNZ on Friday morning.</string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>


</resources>